Richard A. Florsheim Papers
Richard A. Florsheim Papers
- Correspondence-Subject Files
  - Newman, Arnold and Augusta, 1958-1964 (Box 21)
  - Nims, John Frederick and Bonnie, 1951-1952; 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - 1957 Chicago Artists No Jury Exhibition, 1956-1958 (Box 21)
  - North Shore Art League (Winnetka, Ill.), 1947-1962; undated (Box 21)
  - North Truro Art Gallery (North Truro, Mass.), 1962-1965 (Box 21)
  - Northrop, George Norton, 1933-1958 (Box 21)
  - O, 1 folder (Box 21)
  - Oehlschlaeger, Everett, See Oehlschlaeger Galleries (Chicago, Ill.; Sarasota, Fla.)
  - Oehlschlaeger, Frank and Pat, See Oehlschlaeger Galleries (Chicago, Ill.; Sarasota, Fla.)
  - Oehlschlaeger Galleries (Chicago, Ill.; Sarasota, Fla.), 1957-1976; undated; 9 folders (Box 22)
  - Ohio State University, 1956-1957 (Box 22)
  - Oppenheimer, Seymour and Dobs, 1954-1977; undated (Box 22)
  - P, 1 folder (Box 23)
  - Pachner, William, 1956-1959? (Box 23)
  - Packard, David, 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - Pan-American League. Chicago Branch, 1939 (Box 23)
  - Parker, Theresa D. see, See Jacques Seligmann Galleries (New York, N.Y.)
  - Pas S. Leonard, 1964-1976; undated (Box 23)
    See also Illinois Arts Council
  - Pattison, Abbott, 1959?, 1964 (Box 23)
  - Perry, Leo I., 1944-1945 (Box 23)
  - Piers, Maria W., 1970; undated (Box 23)
  - Pijoán, José and family, 1934-1963, (3 folders); undated (Box 23)
  - Pinson, Pierre Louis (Pedro Luis), 1939-1951; undated (Box 23)
  - Piper, Raymond F., 1949-1954 (Box 23)
  - Plaut, Marion, 1934-1939; undated (Box 23)
  - Plaut, Renee, 1941-1964; undated (Box 23)
  - Pollack, Peter
    - 1940-1967, 3 folders (Box 23)
    - 1968-1977, undated, 4 folders (Box 24)
  - Pomerantz, Louis, 1961; 1963,; 1974 (Box 24)
  - Pougialis, Constantine, 1950 (Box 24)
  - Pratt Graphic Art Center (New York, N.Y.) see, See Pratt-Contemporaries Graphic Art Centre (New York, N.Y.)
  - Pratt-Contemporaries Graphic Art Centre (New York, N.Y.), 1957-1966; undated (Box 24)
  - Prior, Dorothy (Mrs. Harris K.), 1960? (Box 24)
  - Provincetown Academy of the Living Arts, 1966-1970; undated (Box 24)
  - Q, 1 folder (Box 24)
  - Quabius, Kempert, 1954?-1956 (Box 24)
  - Quest, Dell, 1940; 1961,; undated (Box 24)
  - Quest Art Galleries (Chicago, Ill.), See Quest, Dell
  - R, 1 folder (Box 24)
  - Ravinia Festival (Ravinia Park, Ill.), 1937; 1955-1959,; undated (Box 24)
  - Ray, Mary, See Gehr, Mary
  - Reeves, Ruth, 1954 (Box 24)
  - Renison, Paula Gerard, See Gerard, Paula
  - Riccardo Studio Restaurant (Chicago, Ill.), 1948-1974; undated (Box 24)
  - Rich, Daniel Catton and Bertha, 1939-1976, (4 folders); undated (Box 24)
  - Richelle Gallery (Saint Louis, Mo.), 1963-1968; undated (Box 25)
  - Rigney, Howard and Margaret, 1970-1977; undated (Box 25)
  - Rissman, Arthur Henry Louis and family, 1954-1972; undated (Box 25)
    See also Chicago Outdoor Art Festivals, Inc.
  - Robertson, Ruth and Sylvan, 1955-1960; undated (Box 25)
  - [Hilyard R.] Robinson, Architect (Washington, D.C.), 1966 (Box 25)
    See also [Republic of] Liberia. Centennial Commission
  - Rockford Art Association (Rockford, Ill.), 1958-1960 (Box 25)
  - Rodde, Michel, 1964 (Box 25)
  - Rogers, Jeanne C., 1942-1958, (2 folders); undated (Box 25)
  - Rogers, John William, 1947-1962 (Box 25)
  - Romano, Clare, 1967 (Box 25)
  - Romano, Umberto (family), 1975; undated (Box 25)
  - Roosevelt College (Chicago, Ill.), 1946 (Box 25)
  - Rosenwald, Lessing J., 1961 (Box 25)
  - Ross, Clare Romano, See Romano, Clare
  - Rothschild, Lincoln, See Artists Equity Association
  - Rubenstein, Betty and Richard, 1973-1977 (Box 25)
  - Rubenstein, Lewis W., 1959; 1966 (Box 25)
  - Ruellan, Andree, 1955-1966 (Box 25)
  - Ruskin, Lewis J., 1941-1948; 1966 (Box 25)
  - Russo, Olga C., 1937-1954; undated (Box 25)
  - Ryan, Sally ("Tammie"), 1940-1941 (Box 25)
  - S, 1 folder (Box 25)
  - Sagourin, Georges, 1953?, 1955?, 1960-1969; undated (Box 25)
  - St. Denis, Ruth, 1950?-1960 (Box 25)
  - Salinas, Marcel, 1967; 1969,; undated (Box 25)
  - Salter, Charlotte, 1968; 1970 (Box 25)
    See also Ashton Gallery (Chestnut Hill, Mass.); Gallery of World Art, Inc. (Newton Center, Mass.)
  - Sawyer, Helen, See Farnsworth, Jerry and Helen Sawyer
  - Scharff, Arthur, 1940 (Box 25)
  - Schloesing, Jean and Jacqueline, 1954-1978; undated (Box 25)
  - Schniewind, Carl O., See Art Institute of Chicago
  - Schniewind, Hedi, 1947 (Box 25)
    See also Little Gallery (Chicago, Ill.)
  - Scholastic Magazines Art Awards, 1954-1958 (Box 25)
  - Scholl, Ruth Wilson, 1950 (Box 25)
  - Schoolcraft, Freeman L., See Artists League of the Midwest
  - Schreckengost, Viktor, 1946-1951 (Box 25)
  - Schwartz, William S., 1949; 1950 (Box 25)
  - Scott, David, 1945 (Box 25)
  - Scott, Henry E. ("Harry"), 1945; 1955 or 1956?,; 1964 (Box 25)
  - Scott, Foresman and Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1950-1951; 1958 (Box 25)
  - Segy, Ladislas, 1939-1949; undated (Box 25)
  - [Jacques] Seligmann Galleries (New York, N.Y.), 1951-1979; undated; 8 folders (Box 26)
  - Shahn, Ben, 1961 (Box 26)
  - Shapiro, Daisy Viertel, 1964-1974 (Box 26)
  - Shapley, Fern, 1955 (Box 26)
  - Shiva, Ramon (Mrs.), 1950 (Box 26)
  - Shopen, Kenneth and Sylvia, 1935-1972; undated (Box 26)
  - Shore Galleries (Boston and Provincetown, Mass.), 1955-1964; undated; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Shulman, Charles E. and Avis, 1942-1958; undated (Box 26)
  - Siegel, Sophie and Adrian, 1955-1957; undated (Box 26)
  - [E. and A.] Silberman Galleries (New York, N.Y.), 1940-1957; 1966,; undated; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Simpson, Louis, 1951; undated (Box 27)
  - Sinaiko, Arlie and Suzanne, 1959-1974; undated (Box 27)
  - Siporin, Mitchell, 1941; 1965 (Box 27)
  - Skotnes, Cecil, 1964; 1967 (Box 27)
  - Society for Contemporary American Art, See Art Institute of Chicago; Robertson, Ruth and Sylvan
  - Sorlier, Charles and family, 1953?, 1955?, 1960-1967; undated (Box 27)
  - South Side Community Art Center (Chicago, Ill.), 1941-1942; undated (Box 27)
  - Sperry, Vicci, 1949; 1950 (Box 27)
  - Stableford, Landon B. and Katherine T., 1950-1970; undated (Box 27)
  - Starr, Milton, 1943-1954; undated (Box 27)
  - Steele, Robert S., 1951-1955; 1975,; undated (Box 27)
    See also Motive (Nashville, Tenn.)
  - Stenvall, John F., 1936; 1949?,; 1955 (Box 27)
  - Stern, Herbert, undated (Box 27)
  - Szecsi, Ladislas, See Segy, Ladislas
  - T, 1 folder (Box 27)
  - Tead, Ordway, 1967-1968 (Box 27)
  - Teillard, Emil, 1937-1940; undated (Box 27)
  - 1020 Art Center (Chicago, Ill.), 1955-1957 (Box 27)
  - Thomas, Edith, 1962-1974; undated (Box 27)
  - Toor, Frances ("Paca"), 1951-1956; undated (Box 27)
  - Tourtelot, Madeline, 1949; 1958 (Box 27)
  - Town & Country Gallery (Mahopac, N.Y.), 1967-1968 (Box 27)
  - Turnbull, James Barre, 1965; 1966 (Box 27)
  - U, 1 folder (Box 27)
  - United States Army (Reserve), 1940-1944; undated (Box 27)
  - United States Navy, See Charles, Clayton and Babe; Clough, Wendell S.; Kremer, William; Newhauser, Herman; Perry, Leo I.; Scott, David; Scott, Henry E.; Vogelgesang, Shepard and Camilla; Watrous, James S. and Peg
    - 1940-1944, 3 folders (Box 27)
    - 1945, undated, 3 folders (Box 28)
  - United States Navy (Reserve), 1947-1950 (Box 28)
  - University of Chicago, 1934-1964; undated (Box 28)
  - University of Wisconsin, 1950-1962 (Box 28)
    See also Midwest College Art Conference (University of Wisconsin-Madison)
  - V, 1 folder (Box 28)
  - Valland, Rose, 1937-1979; undated; 3 folders (Box 28)
  - Van Veen, Stuyvesant, 1967; 1968,; undated (Box 28)
  - Velissaratos, Ruth, 1938; 1939 (Box 28)
  - Viviano, Catherine, 1941; 1949 (Box 28)
  - Viviano, Emmanuel Gerald, 1944; 1948 (Box 28)
  - Vogelgesang, Shepard and Camilla, 1943-1946; undated (Box 28)
  - Von Groschwitz, Gustave, 1953-1964 (Box 28)
  - W, 1 folder (Box 28)
  - Walker, Archie D., 1962-1969 (Box 28)
  - Walker, Hudson D. and family, 1949-1970; undated (Box 28)
  - Walker, Ruth and family, 1958-1970; undated (Box 28)
  - Walley, John Edwin and Jano, 1936-1974 (Box 29)
  - Walter, Bruno, 1946 (Box 29)
  - Watrous, James S. and Peg, 1944-1962 (Box 29)
  - Weber, John, 1969-1970; undated (Box 29)
  - Well of the Sea Gallery (Chicago, Ill.), 1949-1950; undated (Box 29)
  - Western Arts Association, 1950-1956 (Box 29)
  - White, F. Robert, 1942-1943 (Box 29)
  - Williams, Florence and Sam, 1950-1964; undated (Box 29)
  - Wilson, Sol and Dora, 1959-1977 (Box 29)
  - Wolf, Ben and Ruth, 1959-1963; undated (Box 29)
  - Wolf, Henry, 1956 (Box 29)
  - Woods, Gurdon G., 1949 (Box 29)
  - Woodstock Art Conference, 1950 (Box 29)
  - Young, Joseph Louis, 1955; 1959 (Box 29)
  - Zeisler, Richard S., 1958-1974 (Box 29)
  - Ziroli, Nina, 1948 (Box 29)
  - Zwick, Rosemary Goldfein, 1949 (Box 29)
  - Unidentified, 2 folders (Box 29)
- Artwork
  - Reproductions (miscellaneous), 2 folders (Box 30)
- Writings
  - Articles, essays, 1950-1977; mss., printed material (Box 30)
  - Book reviews, 1946-1976; mss., printed material (Box 30)
  - "Diary 1933", ms. (Box 30)
  - Lectures
    - "After Art School", notes (Box 30)
    - "American Art Your Part in Shaping Its Future", ms. (Box 30)
    - "An Artist Looks at the World", notes (Box 30)
    - "An Artist's Point of View", ms., notes (Box 30)
    - "The Arts Today and Tomorrow", research, notes (Box 30)
    - "Business & Art", notes (Box 30)
    - "The Current Outlook for Prints & Printmakers", notes (Box 30)
    - "Government in Art", notes (Box 30)
    - "History of the Arts: an Artist's Point of View", ms. (Box 30)
    - "How a Lithograph Is Made", notes (Box 30)
    - "The Influence of Art in the Community", notes (Box 30)
    - "Is There a Jewish Art?", notes (Box 30)
    - "Issues of Public Concern in the Visual Arts", notes (Box 30)
    - "The Last Ten Years in the Arts -- Confusion or Accomplishment?", ms. (Box 30)
    - "Painting in Chicago", notes (Box 30)
    - "The Place of the Artist in Our Society", ms. (Box 30)
    - "The Predicament of the Arts Today", ms. (Box 30)
    - "Religion in the Fine Arts?", ms. (Box 30)
    - "The State of Art Today", ms. (Box 30)
    - "What an Artist Is", notes (Box 30)
    - "What Do You Expect from Art?", notes (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous untitled, notes (Box 30)
  - "Prose and Verse", 1933 (Box 30)
  - Student papers, 4 folders (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 31)
    See also Correspondence-Subject Files: Freeman, Lucy
- Memorabilia
  - Articles and clippings, 1951-1979; undated (Box 32)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1940s-1980s; undated; 5 folders (Box 32)
  - Exhibition guest registers (2), undated (Box 32)
  - Exhibition invitations, 1950-1979; undated; 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Exhibition poster, undated (Box 32)
  - Financial
    - Artwork prices (Box 32)
    - Studio construction, 1940-1950; undated (Box 32)
  - Lecture related (Box 32)
  - Travel documents (Italy) (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 32)
- Photographs
  - Portraits and Home/Studio, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Social Settings and with Helen Florsheim (wife), (includes formal portrait of Helen Florsheim); 1 folder (Box 33)
  - Early Life, 1 folder (Box 33)
  - Family Photos, 5 folders (Box 33)
  - Portraits and Home/Studio (oversize), (includes formal portrait of Helen Florsheim) (Oversize 1)